<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Cognitivist Subclass</name>
		<description>Wizard who studies mind, thought and conscience.</description>
		<author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Nick_Vendel/">Nick Vendel</author>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="wizard-subclass-cognitivist.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/NickVendel/NV-elements/master/NV/bladetide-setting/realm-of-fauldis/classes/wizard-subclass-cognitivist.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- version 1.1, thanks to Azzy on Discord for help with balancing and wording -->
	<element name="Cognitivist" type="Archetype" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST">
		<supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By reading great amount of books and scrolls, Wizard is able to absorb knowledge of past centuries. From scientific treatises, books of lore and fables to spellcasting theories and magic spells, you've read so much that you lost count, your mind is an archive of theoretical information. This way often linked to deep research in the field of consciousness, memories and learning, due to this people call these Wizards - Cognitive Arcanists, sometimes Cognitive Scientists - which usually shortened to Cognitivists.</p>
			<p class="indent">Followers of this tradition gain power from their memories, that hold knowledge from hundreds if not thousands of books. Many spells are written in their tomes, and bestiaries hold facts that even the great scientists of their time may not know about.</p>
			<div element="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_POLYGLOT" />
			<div element="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER" />
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER_SPELL_WAND_MAKING" />
			</div>
			<div element="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MIND_ARCHIVE" />
			<div element="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_SECRETS_OF_THE_BESTIARY" />
			<div element="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_ONE_IN_A_MILLION" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Followers of this tradition gain power from their memories, that hold knowledge from hundreds if not thousands of books. Many spells are written in their tomes, and bestiaries hold facts that even the great scientists of their time may not know about.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_POLYGLOT" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MIND_ARCHIVE" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_SECRETS_OF_THE_BESTIARY" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_ONE_IN_A_MILLION" level="14"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Polyglot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_POLYGLOT">
		<requirements>!ID_NV_FLDS_CFV_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_POLYGLOT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:5px"><i>2nd-level Cognitivist feature</i></p>
			<p style="margin-top:0px">You're able to recall relevant parts from books of different languages in order to gain great insight into languages you don't know. Whenever you hear or read language you don't know, you can use your Action to temporarily understand and speak it as if you were a typical speaker, after 1 hour you lose this insight. If you hear multiple languages, you must choose one to gain this insight with. You can use this ability number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1) after each long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="{{polyglot:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>Whenever you hear or read language you don't know, you can gain temporarily understanding and ability to speak it as if you were a typical speaker, after 1 hour you lose this insight. If you hear multiple languages, you must choose one to gain this insight with.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="polyglot:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="polyglot:usage" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Magic Wand Master" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:5px"><i>2nd-level Cognitivist feature</i></p>
			<p style="margin-top:0px">In each generation of Wizards you can find concepts and instructions on how to create and use magical wands, you adapt best parts for your own process. You gain following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Wand Making:</b> Whenever you finish short or long rest, you can create <i>Wand of Accuracy</i> with following materials: a scroll on which you draw a transmutation pentagram, small wooden stick (or any metal bar) and leather strips. <i>Wand of Accuracy</i> allows user's spell attacks to ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.
				When you gain 6th level in this class, you can create or re-enchant previously created (doesn't require new materials) <i>Wand of Accuracy</i> that, in addition to previous properties, also gains enchantment bonus +1 to user's spell attacks and spell DC. Enchantment bonus of newly created or re-enchanted wands increases further to +2 at 12th, and to +3 at 18th level in this class.</li>
				<li><b>Smart Wand:</b> Whenever you're targeted by a harmful spell or receive damage from a harmful spell, and hold a wand in your hand, you can use your reaction to collect and use residual energy of the spell to power your wand. If you're holding a spell wand, for example Wand of Magic Missile, and it has needed amount of charges, you can activate and use it. Otherwise, you gain additional +1 bonus to attack, DC and damage of your next spell. You can use this ability number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1) after each long rest.
				Additionally, you can perform the somatic components of spells with any magic wand.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER_WAND_MAKING" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER_SMART_WAND" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Optional Rule (Bad Balance): Spell Wand Making" type="Rule" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER_SPELL_WAND_MAKING">
		<description>
			<p>DM can also allow you to create spell wands. By replacing pentagram scroll with spell scroll, you can use gem of appropriate value (see table below) to create one wand with that spell. Spell wand of basic level contains 10 charges, with each being able to produce a spell of its basic level. Spell wand regains one charge at dawn. You can use more valuable gem to receive enchanting bonus, each tier of which wand gains additional charge and allows to cast spell at a level higher, as if you're using spell slot of a higher level. If spell doesn't have ability to use spell slots of a higher level, then spell gains +1 bonus to attack, damage and DC for each tier over its basic level.</p>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Gem's value</td><td class="col-5">Spell level</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>500 gp</td><td class="col-5">Cantrip or 1st level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>1000 gp</td><td class="col-5">2nd level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>1500 gp</td><td class="col-5">3rd level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2000 gp</td><td class="col-5">4th level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2500 gp</td><td class="col-5">5th level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10000 gp</td><td class="col-5">6th level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20000 gp</td><td class="col-5">7th level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>30000 gp</td><td class="col-5">8th level</td></tr>
				<tr><td>100000 gp</td><td class="col-5">9th level</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
	</element>
	<element name="Wand Making" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER_WAND_MAKING">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you finish short or long rest, you can create <i>Wand of Accuracy</i> with following items: a scroll on which you draw a transmutation pentagram, small wooden stick (or any metal bar) and leather strips. <i>Wand of Accuracy</i> allows user's spell attacks to ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you gain 6th level in this class, you can create or re-enchant previously created (doesn't require new components) <i>Wand of Accuracy</i> that, in addition to previous properties, also gains enchantment bonus +1 to user's spell attacks and spell DC. Enchantment bonus of newly created or re-enchanted wands increases further to +2 at 12th, and to +3 at 18th level in this class.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you finish short or long rest, you can create Wand of Accuracy with following items: a scroll on which you draw a transmutation pentagram, small wooden stick (or any metal bar) and leather strips. Wand of Accuracy allows user's spell attacks to ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.</description>
			<description level="6">Whenever you finish short or long rest, you can create Wand of Accuracy with following items: a scroll on which you draw a transmutation pentagram, small wooden stick (or any metal bar) and leather strips. Wand of Accuracy allows user's spell attacks to ignore half cover and three-quarters cover. Additionally, newly created or re-enchanted Wands of Accuracy gain enchantment bonus +{{wand making:enchantment bonus}} to user's spell attacks and spell DC.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="wand making:enchantment bonus" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="wand making:enchantment bonus" value="2" bonus="base" level="12"/>
			<stat name="wand making:enchantment bonus" value="3" bonus="base" level="18"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Smart Wand" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MAGIC_WAND_MASTER_SMART_WAND">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you're targeted by a harming spell or receive damage from a harming spell, and hold a wand in your hand, you can use your reaction to collect and use residual energy of the spell to power your wand. If you're holding a spell wand, for example Wand of Magic Missile, and it has needed amount of charges, you can activate and use it. Otherwise, you gain additional +1 bonus to attack, DC and damage of your next spell. You can use this ability number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1) after each long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you can perform the somatic components of spells with any magic wand.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{smart wand:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>Whenever you're targeted by a harming spell or receive damage from a harming spell, and hold a wand in your hand, you can collect and use residual energy of the spell to power your wand. If you're holding a spell wand and it has needed amount of charges, you can activate and use it. Otherwise, you gain additional +1 bonus to attack, DC and damage of your next spell. Additionally, you can perform the somatic components of spells with any magic wand.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="smart wand:usage" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="smart wand:usage" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mind Archive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_MIND_ARCHIVE">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:5px"><i>6th-level Cognitivist feature</i></p>
			<p style="margin-top:0px">Your mind sorts every piece of information that it stores with ease, helping with access to needed memories and allowing you to imitate abilities of legendary historical figures.</p>
			<p class="indent">After each long rest you can choose between any Metamagic or Expertise. When selecting Expertise, choose any skill that you're proficient with, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any checks you make with it. Alternatively, you can choose one Metamagic from ones described in Sorcerer class in <i>Player's Handbook</i> (on pages 101-102), you gain sorcery points equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 2), these points are added to any sorcery points you have from another source but can be used only on Metamagic. This effect lasts until you finish next long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>After each long rest you can choose between any Metamagic or Expertise. When selecting Expertise, choose any skill that you're proficient with, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any checks you make with it. Alternatively, you can choose one Metamagic and gain {{sorcery-points}} sorcery points to power your Metamagic. This effect lasts until you finish next long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="sorcery-points" value="2" bonus="mind archive"/>
			<stat name="sorcery-points" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="mind archive"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Secrets of the Bestiary" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_SECRETS_OF_THE_BESTIARY">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:5px"><i>10th-level Cognitivist feature</i></p>
			<p style="margin-top:0px">You fill your bestiary with everything about monsters, races and other creatures that you know. You can spend 1 minute looking through your bestiary, to find useful info about a particular creature type. When you do so, you and number of your allies equal to 2 + Intelligence modifier, that can hear you, gain one benefit that you choose from the following list:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Aberration:</b> You know about dangers that these completely alien creatures pose to Prime Material Plane. One time, whenever you fail a saving throw forced upon you by an Aberration, you can choose to succeed instead, if not used you lose this ability after 1 hour.</li>
				<li><b>Beast:</b> You studied natural habitats and hunting behaviors of dangerous animals. You gain advantage on saving throws against being poisoned, knocked prone or grappled which forced upon you by a Beast creature.</li>
				<li><b>Celestial:</b> You know well about innate magical abilities and resistances of celestials, creatures under the will of higher powers. Your spells and magical abilities ignore Magical Resistance trait of Celestial creatures, or when you hit Celestial creature that doesn't have this trait with a spell, magical ability or magical attack, you can add a d8 to one damage roll.</li>
				<li><b>Construct:</b> You're well versed in technology and magic that's used for creating constructs, as such you know multiple ways of disassembling them. When dealing damage to Constructs you ignore their resistances and immunities to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
				<li><b>Dragon:</b> These both stunning and terrifying creatures leave behind a multitude of legends, fables and myths, but for you it's not that hard to find useful information about dragons. One time, whenever you fail a saving throw forced upon you by Breath (or any other Rechargeable) action of a Dragon creature, you can choose to succeed instead, if not used you lose this ability after 1 hour. Additionally, you gain advantage on saving throws against Frightful Presence.</li>
				<li><b>Elemental:</b> Creatures of Elemental Planes gain power from their respective element, but you know ways to break that magical link. When you deal damage to an Elemental, you ignore their resistances to acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison or thunder damage types, and you treat immunities to those types of damage as resistances.</li>
				<li><b>Fey:</b> You're aware of creatures known as fey, and their usually chaotic and deceiving nature. You gain advantage on any Wisdom or Intelligence saving throw forced upon you by a Fey creature.</li>
				<li><b>Fiend:</b> Just reading about these creatures felt like someone or something was watching you, but you understand that even fiends have their weaknesses. Your spells and magical abilities ignore Magical Resistance trait of Fiends, or when you hit Fiend creature that doesn't have this trait with a spell, magical ability or magical attack, you can add a d8 to one damage roll.</li>
				<li><b>Giant:</b> You know well that colossal creatures known as giants can be dangerous foes, but knowing your enemy is the half of the battle. If your size is equal or larger than size of the Giant creature, your attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 against it, or if you're smaller than Giant you can go through its space and exit its range without provoking opportunity attacks, but you must end your turn in unoccupied space.</li>
				<li><b>Humanoid:</b> You studied humanoid biology and physiology, and know weak spots of most, if not all, humanoid races. When you hit Humanoid creature, you can add a d12 to one damage roll, if attack was made with advantage.</li>
				<li><b>Monstrosity:</b> You studied different monstrosities, and predatory battle tactics that they use against humanoids. When Monstrosity hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that Monstrosity for the rest of the turn.</li>
				<li><b>Ooze:</b> Shapeless and usually mindless creatures that resemble oozes, would deceive ignorant human, but you know how to avoid their hazardous abilities. You deal double fire damage to all Oozes, but resistances and immunities to fire damage still apply. Additionally, one time when Ooze creature uses its reaction to Split, you can use your reaction to attack it with advantage before it multiplies, if this attack drops creature to lower than 10 hit points Ooze wastes its reaction and is unable to Split, if not used you lose this ability after 1 hour.</li>
				<li><b>Plant:</b> Intelligent flora can sometimes be as alluring and wondrous as predatory and vicious, you know enough to be fooled by this mimicry. If you deal fire damage to Plant creature that doesn't have resistance or immunity to fire damage, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end of its next turn. Additionally, if your Passive Perception is higher than 10 + Plant creature's CR, you can see through its False Appearance.</li>
				<li><b>Undead:</b> Living dead are created unnatural magical experiments or natural disasters that bind spiritual energy to a location, you know few ways to turn undead into dust. Whenever you deal critical hit to Undead creature whose CR less or equal to half your level, it is automatically destroyed, or if its CR is higher, you deal four times the damage instead of double.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">These benefits last 1 hour, unless specified otherwise. Once you use this ability you need to finish short or long rest, before using it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="1 Minute" usage="1/Rest">
			<description>You and number of your allies equal to 2 + {{intelligence:modifier}}, that can hear you, gain one benefit that you choose from the following list: 
			• Aberration – one time you fail a saving throw forced upon you by an Aberration, you can choose to succeed instead, if not used you lose this ability after 1 hour; 
			• Beast – you gain advantage on saving throws against being poisoned, knocked prone or grappled which forced upon you by a Beast creature; 
			• Celestial – your spells and magical abilities ignore Magical Resistance trait of Celestial creatures, or when you hit Celestial creature that doesn't have this trait with a spell, magical ability or magical attack, you can add a d8 to one damage roll; 
			• Construct – when dealing damage to Constructs you ignore their resistances and immunities to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage; 
			• Dragon – one time, whenever you fail a saving throw forced upon you by Breath (or any other Rechargeable) action of a Dragon creature, you can choose to succeed instead, if not used you lose this ability after 1 hour. Additionally, you gain advantage on saving throws against Frightful Presence; 
			• Elemental – when you deal damage to an Elemental, you ignore their resistances to acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison or thunder damage types, and you treat immunities to those types of damage as resistances; 
			• Fey – You gain advantage on any Wisdom or Intelligence saving throw forced upon you by a Fey creature; 
			• Fiend – Your spells and magical abilities ignore Magical Resistance trait of Fiends, or when you hit Fiend creature that doesn't have this trait with a spell, magical ability or magical attack, you can add a d8 to one damage roll; 
			• Giant – If your size is equal or larger than size of the Giant creature, your attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 against it, or if you're smaller than Giant you can go through its space and exit its range without provoking opportunity attacks, but you must end your turn in unoccupied space; 
			• Humanoid – when you hit Humanoid creature, you can add a d12 to one damage roll, if attack was made with advantage; 
			Monstrosity – when Monstrosity hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that Monstrosity for the rest of the turn; 
			• Ooze – you deal double fire damage to all Oozes, but resistances and immunities to fire damage still applies. Additionally, one time when Ooze creature uses its reaction to Split, you can use your reaction to attack it with advantage before it multiplies, if this attack drops creature to lower than 10 hit points Ooze wastes its reaction and is unable to Split, if not used you lose this ability after 1 hour; 
			• Plant – If you deal fire damage to Plant creature that doesn't have resistance or immunity to fire damage, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the end of its next turn. Additionally, if your Passive Perception is higher than 10 + Plant creature's CR, you can see through its False Appearance; 
			• Undead – whenever you deal critical hit to Undead creature whose CR less or equal to half your level, it is automatically destroyed, or if its CR is higher, you deal four times the damage instead of double. 
			These benefits last 1 hour, unless specified otherwise.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="One in a Million" type="Archetype Feature" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_WIZARD_SUBCLASS_COGNITIVIST_ONE_IN_A_MILLION">
		<description>
			<p style="margin-bottom:5px"><i>14th-level Cognitivist feature</i></p>
			<p style="margin-top:0px">Your research allows you to get around limits of your conscience and gain further control over your body. You gain following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li><b>Limitless:</b> From this point on you mind enters a new phase of development, and your maximum for Intelligence score becomes 24.</li>
				<li><b>One Mind:</b> Full control over your conscience gives you advantage on saving throws against charming, dominating, and other mind-controlling effects, including those that take control over your body or paralyze you.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="One Mind">
			<description>Full control over your conscience gives you advantage on saving throws against charming, dominating, and other mind-controlling effects, including those that take control over your body or paralyze you.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:max" value="4" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>