<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Spells from the Realm of Fauldis</name>
		<author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Nick_Vendel/">Nick Vendel</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/NickVendel/NV-elements/master/NV/bladetide-setting/realm-of-fauldis/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Arcane Coat" type="Spell" source="Bladetide: Realm of Fauldis" id="ID_NV_FLDS_SPELL_ARCANE_COAT">
		<supports>Wizard, Warlock, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p><b>History:</b> This cantrip was created by a powerful Human Wizard Nemira Coldash and was later named <i>Nemira's Black Staff</i> by her colleagues, due to Nemira's skills when fighting with a quarterstaff and using this spell to cover staff with black coat. Later, after it was recreated for use by Sorcerers and, incidentally, Warlocks, spell became famous as <i>Arcane Blade</i>, due to increased usage among orders of Battlemages. It was finally included in Tomes of Magic under a name <i>Arcane Coat</i>, as a compromise between actual spell mechanics and famous nickname.</p>
			<p>When you touch a melee weapon, which lacks two-handed or heavy property, you cover it with a magical coating, which increases weapon's durability and power. For the duration, you can use your spellcasting ability instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of that weapon, and the weapon’s damage die becomes a d6. The weapon also becomes magical, if it isn’t already. The spell ends at the end of the turn if you let go of the weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The damage die of the weapon affected by this spell increases to a d8 at 11th level.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">weapon, Nemira's black staff, arcane blade</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">small natural sponge, and a weapon that caster holds in their hand</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


</elements>